volkswagen.co.uk 2019-05-03

# Volkswagen | Privacy statement

  * ### Privacy statement

  * ### Cookie policy

  * ### Our cookies

  * ### Third party cookies

  * ### Volkswagen Community Guidelines

**Volkswagen UK** , a trading division of Volkswagen Group United Kingdom Limited (“we”/”us”) are committed to protecting and respecting any personal information you share with us.

This statement describes what types of information we collect from you, how it is used by us, how we share it with others, how you can manage the information we hold and how you can contact us.

We will always give you the option not to receive marketing communications from us. We will never send you unsolicited ‘junk’ email or communications, or share your data with anyone else who might. We do not sell your information to third parties, but we do work closely with selected partners who help us to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us. For example, the AA who provide roadside assistance on our behalf.

The contents of this statement may change from time to time so you may wish to check this page occasionally to ensure you are still happy to share your information with us. Where possible, we will also contact you directly to notify you of any substantial  changes.

This version of our Privacy Statement is live from 17th July 2018.

### **What information do we collect?**

_We collect information about you and your vehicle when you engage with our website, applications or authorised repairer network. We only collect information which is necessary, relevant and adequate for the purpose you are providing it for._

Read more __

We collect information about you or your vehicle when you use Volkswagen UK’s websites, applications and our customer service centres. We also obtain information about you or your vehicle from our authorised repairers. Some of this information does not identify you personally, but provides us with information about how you use our services and engage with us (we use this information to improve our services and make them more useful to you). The information we collect includes some or all of the following:

  1. Name (including title);
  2. Address;
  3. Phone number;
  4. Date of birth;
  5. Email address;
  6. Vehicle information (including registration number, VIN, service reminders, mileage and warranty repair information);
  7. The date and time you used our services;
  8. The pages you visited on our website and how long you visited us for;
  9. Your IP address;
  10. Your GPS location (where you have permitted access to this);
  11. The internet browser and devices you are using;
  12. Cookie, Pixels or Beacon information (for more information please see our Cookie Policy);
  13. The website address from which you accessed our website;
  14. Details of any transactions between you and us or any authorised repairer;
  15. Where you engage with us in a business context, we may collect your job title, company contact details (including email addresses), fleet size and company details (some of which we may obtain from an online or public business directories);
  16. Voice recordings of calls you make to our customer service centre;
  17. “Live chat” records; and
  18. Any information within correspondence you send to us.
  19. Where you act on behalf of a business, any information we collect as part of business telemarketing activity

### **How do we use this information?**

_Volkswagen UK will only process information that is necessary for the purpose for which it has been collected. You will always have the option not to receive marketing communications from us (and you can withdraw your consent or object at any time). We will never send you unsolicited ‘junk’ email or communications, or share  your personal information with anyone else who might._

Read more __

There are various ways in which we may use or process your personal information.  We list these below:

**Consent**

Where you have provided your consent, we may use and process your information to:

  1. Contact you from time to time about promotions, events, products, services or information which we think may be of interest to you (don’t worry, we won’t bombard you);
  2. Use automatic number plate recognition when you visit our authorised repairer network to alert them to your arrival at their premises.
  3. To share your personal information with our recommended third party partners, so that they can contact you with marketing information about their products and services (we will, of course, give you details about these third parties before you give your permission for us to send information to them).

You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us on the details provided within the 'How can I manage the information we hold about you' section below or, in relation to any marketing messages you receive, by using the unsubscribe option included in those messages.

**Contractual performance**

We may use and process your personal information where this is necessary to perform a contract with you and to fulfil and complete your orders, purchases and other transactions entered into with us (or one of our authorised repairers or selected partners).

**Legitimate interests**

We may use and process your personal information as set out below where it is necessary for us to carry out activities for which it is in our legitimate interests as a business to do so.

**Processing necessary for us to support customers with sales and other enquiries**

1. To respond to correspondence you send to us and fulfil the requests you make to us (for example: test drives, service requests, brochure requests or information about specific vehicles);

2. To provide vehicle support and services (for example warranty services);

**Processing necessary for us to respond to understanding customers’ and drivers’ needs**

3. To analyse, evaluate and improve our products and services so that your visit and use of our website, applications, customer service centre and authorised repairer network are more useful and enjoyable (we will generally use data amalgamated from many people so that it doesn’t identify you personally).

4\. To provide service, maintenance and warranty information and reminders, unless you object.

5. To undertake market analysis and research (including contacting you with customer surveys) so that we can better understand you as a customer and provide tailored offers, products and services that we think you will be interested in. We will only send marketing communications to you if you have provided your consent for us to do so or which we have obtained in the ways mentioned in the paragraphs above;

6. For product development purposes (for example to improve vehicle quality, performance and safety);

7. In some cases we may use automated methods to analyse, combine and evaluate information that you have provided to us (including the sharing of your personal information within our group of companies: Volkswagen Financial Services (UK) Limited, Volkswagen AG, Audi AG, SEAT S.A., SKODA AUTO a.s). We collect and analyse this information in this way so that we can deliver the most appropriate customer experience to you by tailoring and making relevant all our service and communications (for example, when your mileage suggests your vehicle is due for a service);

**Processing necessary for us to promote our business, brands and products and measure the reach and effectiveness of our campaigns**

8. To send you marketing information from time to time after you have purchased a product or service from us or made a purchasing enquiry, closed your browser with items in your shopping basket or requested a test drive, brochure or other information of interest. We will only contact you with information about our own products and services (and in ways the law allows), which we hope you will like. You have the right to object to us sending you this information at any time;

9. To contact you from time to time with marketing information (unless you object) if you have expressly indicated to us that you are acting on behalf of a business or where we have obtained your business contact details from our authorised repairer network or an online or public business directory. In relation to any such information we send by email or SMS, we will include an option allowing you to object to receiving future messages by unsubscribing;

10. To contact you with targeted advertising delivered online through social media and other platforms operated by other companies, unless you object. You may receive advertising based on information about you that we have provided to the platform or because, at our request, the platform has identified you as having similar attributes to the individuals whose details it has received from us. To find out more, please refer to the information provided in the help pages of the platforms on which you receive advertising from us; To send you information on our extended warranty products where you are benefiting from a current Volkswagen warranty and it is about to expire. You have the right to object to us sending this information at any time _;_

11. To identify and record when you have received, opened or engaged with our website or electronic communications (please see our Cookie Policy for more information);

12. To administer competitions and promotions that you enter with us from time to time and to distribute prizes;

13\. To contact you when your local authorised dealer / retailer opens, closes or moves premises.

**Processing necessary for us to operate the administrative and technical aspects of our business efficiently and effectively**

14. To verify the accuracy of information that we hold about you and create a better understanding of you as a customer;

15. For network and information security purposes i.e. in order for us to take steps to protect your information against loss, damage, theft or unauthorised access;

16. To comply with a request from you in connection with the exercise of your rights (for example where you have asked us not to contact you for marketing purposes, we will keep a record of this on our suppression lists in order to be able to comply with your request);

17. To inform you of updates to our terms and conditions and policies.

**Legal obligation**

We may process your personal information to comply with our legal requirements (for example to register your car with the DVLA).

**Vital interest**

Sometimes we will need to process your personal information to contact you if there is an urgent safety or product recall notice and we need to tell you about it.

### **How do we share this information?**

_We do not sell your information to third parties, but we do work closely with our authorised repairer network and with third party suppliers who fulfil business activities for us (like roadside assistance, marketing, events and market research etc.)_

Read more __

We do not sell your information to third parties. However, we may from time to time disclose your information to the following categories of companies or organisations to which we pass the responsibility to handle services on our behalf: roadside assistance service providers, customer contact centres, mobility and car hire providers, direct marketing communications agencies and consultants, market research and market analytics service providers, our legal and other professional advisors.

We will also share your information with our authorised repairer network in situations where we need to pass your information to them in order to manage any request or complaint you have made to us. For example, where you have requested a test drive, we will need to share your personal information with your selected authorised repairer so that they can contact you to arrange for the test drive to take place.

We take steps to ensure that any third-party partners who handle your information comply with data protection legislation and protect your information just as we do. We only disclose personal information that is necessary for them to provide the service that they are undertaking on our behalf. We will aim to anonymise your information or use aggregated none specific data sets where ever possible.

Due to the international nature of our business, there may be some instances where your information is processed or stored outside of the EU.  In those instances, we will ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place for that transfer and storage as required by applicable law. 

There are circumstances where we share your information with our parent (or other companies within our Group) in order to fulfil orders, transactions, handle complaints or provide you with a service or information that you have requested. For example; we will share information with Volkswagen Financial Services UK Limited where you enquire about their services through us or where you make a complaint to us and later make the same or similar complaint to them. Volkswagen Financial Services UK Limited may use your information to provide you with information and carry out their obligations arising from contracts you enter into with them.  For more information, please see their [privacy statement](https://www.vwfs.co.uk/en/home/legal_notice.html).

### **How long do we keep your information for?**

_We will not hold your personal information in an identifiable format for any longer than is necessary. If you are a customer or otherwise have a relationship with us we will hold personal information about you for a longer period than if we have obtained your details in connection with a prospective relationship._

Read more __

We do not retain personal information in an identifiable format for longer than is necessary.

If we have a relationship with you (e.g. you are a customer or the registered driver of a leased or other vehicle purchased from us or an authorised repairer), we hold your personal information for 6 years from the date our relationship ends. We hold your personal information for this period to establish, bring or defend legal claims.  Our relationship may end for a number of reasons including where the vehicle warranty or lease expires, or we have been made aware that you no longer own or drive that vehicle.

Where we have obtained your personal information following a request for information, test drive, brochure, quotation or any other information on any of our products or services, we hold your personal information for 1 year and 6 months from the date we collect that information, unless during that period we form a relationship with you e.g. you purchase or lease a vehicle.  We hold your personal information for this period to give us an opportunity to form a relationship with you.

The only exceptions to the periods mentioned above are where:

  * The law requires us to hold your personal information for a longer period, or delete it sooner;
  * Where you have raised a legal claim, complaint or concern regarding a product or service offered by us, in which case we will retain your information for a period of 6 years following the date of that complaint or query; or
  * You exercise your right to have the information erased (where it applies) and we do not need to hold it in connection with any of the reasons permitted or required under the law (see further How can I manage the information we hold about you);

### **How can I manage the information we hold about you?  **

_You have the right as an individual to access your personal information we hold about you and make corrections if necessary. You also have the right to withdraw any consent you have previously given us and ask us to erase information we hold about you. You can also object to us using your personal information (where we rely on our business interests to process and use your personal information)._

Read more __

You have a number of rights in relation to your personal information under data protection law. In relation to most rights, we will ask you for information to confirm your identity and, where applicable, to help us search for your personal information. Except in rare cases, we will respond to you within 30 days after we have received any request (including any identification documents requested).

You have the right to:

  1. Ask for a copy of the information that we hold about you;
  2. Correct and update your information;
  3. Withdraw your consent (where we rely on it). Please see further How do we use this information;
  4. Object to our use of your information (where we rely on our legitimate interests to use your personal information) provided we do not have any continuing lawful reason to continue to use and process the information.  When we do rely on our legitimate interests to use your personal information for direct marketing, we will always comply with your right to object;
  5. Erase your information (or restrict the use of it), provided we do not have any continuing lawful reason to continue to use and process that information;
  6. Transfer your information in a structured data file (in a commonly used and machine readable format), where we rely on your consent to use and process your personal information or need to process it in connection with your contract.

You can exercise the above rights and/or manage your information by contacting us using the details below:

**Post:  **Volkswagen Customer Care, Selectapost 12, Sheffield, S97 3ZU 

**Email:**  [customerservices@volkswagen.co.uk](mailto:customerservices@volkswagen.co.uk)

If you are unhappy, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection regulator in Europe, in particular in a country you work or live or where your legal rights have been infringed.  The contact details for the Information Commissioner’s Office, the data protection regulator in the UK, are below:

Post:   Information Commissioner's Office  
            Wycliffe House  
            Water Lane  
            Wilmslow  
            Cheshire  
            SK9 5AF

Call:     [0303 123 1113](tel:03031231113)

Email:   [casework@ico.org.uk](mailto:casework@ico.org.uk)

### What are cookies?

"Cookies" are small text files that are stored on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website.

They allow the website to recognise your device and remember if you've been to the website before.

Cookies are very common web technology - most websites use cookies and have done for years. Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work more efficiently, as well as providing information to the owners of websites.

Cookies are used to measure which parts of the website people visit and to customise your experience. Cookies also provide information that helps us monitor and improve the website's performance.

You can read more about the different types of cookies that we use on this website on this page.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your computer and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/)

We use cookies to enhance the performance of our website and personalise your online Volkswagen experience.

Cookies help us to collect information on how people use our website and which pages they visit. They enable us to monitor the number of visitors and to analyse website usage patterns and trends.

We collect this information anonymously, so it doesn't identify anyone as an individual and no personal information is stored in our cookies. We always use cookie data in a responsible way.

Our aim is to continually improve the Volkswagen online experience. Cookies help to make our website work better and more efficiently. However, if you want to find out more on how to disable cookies you can do so here: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/).

### **Cookie name**

| 

### **Cookie purpose**  
  
---|---  
bdl-uuid  
bdl-ltap  |  These cookies save visitors time when filling in forms by remembering the details entered into contact forms to allow pre-population of forms the next time.   
_s3_id.60.c5c7  
captcha  
k2c_VWUK_cids  
k2c_history  
k2c_VWUKBlank  
omnitureViewTracked  
s_vi  
s_ria  
s_cc  
s_sq  
s_nr  
s_ev71  
sc_prevCE  
s_sv_sid  
s_campaign  
s_sv_p1  
s_sv_s1  |  These cookies store website usage data to allow us to understand information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers and responses to marketing activity.   
JSESSIONID  
PHPSESSID  
SERVERID  
ico-cookies  |  A functional cookie required by our web servers to respond to your actions. This cookie is required for the website to work.   
siteReferrer  |  This cookie allows us to see how visitors have found their way to [Volkswagen.co.uk](http://volkswagen.co.uk/).   
flashReferrer  
flash  |  This cookie helps us to optimise visitor experience by showing us how visitors are referred from Flash to HTML sections of [Volkswagen.co.uk](http://volkswagen.co.uk/).   
sifrFetch  |  This cookie prevents needless loading of existing information. It allows Adobe Flash sections of [Volkswagen.co.uk](http://volkswagen.co.uk/) to remember what fonts it already has.   
fbOpen  
fbOpenUrl  
fbRating  
fbInfo  
fbName  
fbEmail  
fbSection  
FeedbackUid  |  These cookies help to improve the site by allowing us to receive the feedback that visitors leave.   
defaultRetailerId  
default_retailer  |  These cookies optimise navigation and allow visitors to find Volkswagen retailer information by allowing our website to remember which Volkswagen retailer visitors have selected.   
ccd_customer  |  This cookie allows us to remember which visitors have selected to view Company Car Driver sections of the website to display the correct content.   
ab-mm  |  From time to time, we test new features of our website. This cookie allows us to track usage information for any new feature testing we run.   
_ _utma  
_ _utmb  
_ _utmc  
_ _utmz  
_ga  
_gat  
NID  |  These cookies help us optimise the website by allowing us to track generic website usage statistics.   
vw-user-cookie  |  This cookie remembers your login information.   
VW_DISPLAY_NAME  |  This cookie remembers your name details.   
CampaignUid  |  This cookie allows us to remember when users book test drives through Volkswagen campaigns.   
_userSelectedFilter  |  This cookie allows visitors to use the model comparison section of the website.   
configuration_v8  |  This cookie allows visitors to use the model configuration section of the website.   
ab-hc-g  
ab-golf-val  
ab-golf-vii  
ab-faqs-contact  |  This cookie allows visitors to see different views of the website.   
shownWelcomeMessage  |  Timeline cookie set once visitors have viewed the welcome message.   
td_cvp  |  This cookie helps us to optimise visitor experience for test drive.   
volkswagenUKBookAService  |  This cookie helps us to manage service booking experience.   
vw-personalisation-panedcontent  
vw-personalisation-paragraph  |  This cookie provides users with a personalised experience.   
AWSELB  |  Elastic Load Balancing creates a cookie, named AWSELB, that is used to map the session to the instance.   
sd_nps_client  |  This cookie is used for a random sample survey to continuously improve the website.   
SMARTDIGITAL_ENSIGHTEN_PRIVACY_BANNER_VIEWED  |  This cookie is set after the user has closed the Policy Notification cookie.   
smartSignals2UiD  |  This cookie contains an anonymous unique ID for a website user. This ID is used to recognize the user over different sessions and to track their activities on the website. This data is used to analyze and improve the site.   
SmartUID  |  This cookie contains an anonymous, unique ID for a website user. This ID is used to recognize the user over different sessions and to track their activities on the website. The data collected in this way is used for the (anonymous) individualised playout of content.   
SMARTDIGITAL_ENSIGHTEN_PRIVACY_MODAL_VIEWED  |  This cookie is set to control the display of the modal to cookie choice.   
  
Third party cookies may come from partners that provide functional web tools for our site, other websites where we advertise and from social networks.

**Examples of third party cookies:**

**Functional web tools:** We offer some useful tools on [Volkswagen.co.uk](https://www.volkswagen.co.uk/), such as the Volkswagen Used Car Locator which requires cookies from other Volkswagen group websites in order to allow it to find cars near to you.

**Social network sharing:** If you share content from [Volkswagen.co.uk](https://www.volkswagen.co.uk/) using social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, you may be sent cookies from these websites.

**Volkswagen advertising:** We sometimes advertise on other websites. These adverts use third party cookies to help them to display personalised ads that are relevant to you.

If you want to find out more on cookies please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/)

### **Cookie name**

| 

### **Cookie purpose**  
  
---|---  
psyma_participation  |  This cookie is used to indicate your participation in the Psyma online survey, as well as to prevent multiple invitations during a visit to this website whilst the survey is live (approx. 30 days). It does not contain any data from the survey or any reference to the individual visitor.   
poi  |  This cookie helps us improve your online experience with Volkswagen by linking user survey participation information to our analytics system.   
id  
ug  
bh  
uid  
ac  
acid  
ADJG  
ajrbds  
ajuserguid  
anh  
anj  
anon_id  
awselb  
b  
bi80654  
c  
c2  
cav  
CfP  
csv  
cc  
cdp  
cmd  
cmp  
cms  
d  
e  
eid  
f  
hl  
i  
identitytoken  
jeb2  
khaos  
mc  
nscfld17efmflqppmflttm  
NSC_d17efm_qppm_ttm  
nxclick2  
oax  
pa  
pad  
pixelehovpba  
pixelnccarkhf  
pixeltbbtyr  
pixelthzthz  
putfl  
ra1_sid  
ra1_uid  
ra1_sgm_1830204518  
ra1flsgm  
ra1flsgmfl  
ra1flsid  
ra1fluid  
ra1balancer  
rpb  
rpx  
rud  
ruds  
sess  
tapad_did  
tapad_ts  
tid  
tuuid  
u  
ug  
uid  
uuid  
uuid2  
um  
umeh  
visit_id  |  Sometimes we advertise on third party websites. These cookies are used to help us see which advertisements visitors interact with.   
_ _uset  |  When visitors share content from our site, this cookie allows us to see what areas of the website are popular.   
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
GEUP  
YSC  
PREF  |  This cookie allows YouTube to collect usage information for YouTube hosted videos.   
TCSess  
TCID  
_qst_s  
_qsst_s  |  These cookies enable analytics software which helps us to understand information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers and responses to marketing activity.   
datr  
lsd  
reg_ext_ref  
reg_fb_gate  
reg_fb_ref  
wd  |  These cookies allow Facebook users to interact with the website and share content.   
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmt  
_utmv  
_utmz  
_twitter_sess  
external_referer  
guest_id  
k  
original_referer  |  These cookies allow Twitter users to interact with the website and share content.   
evo5  
ev4  
tcid  
tcsess  |  This cookie is used to collect information about users browsing behaviour for marketing purposes.   
ASP.NET_SessionId  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  
last-se-wflw  
last-wflw  
pst-pcde  
last[se_ce_]-[ctr]-arg  
vtp  
fav-vhl-list  
aenq-vhl-list  |  Functional cookies set by the Used Car Locator. These cookies allow users to search for used Volkswagen cars.   
_gat_astuteTracker  
am-link  
am-ref  
ga-custom2  
ga-custom3  
ga-custom4A  
ga-custom4B  
ga-custom4C  
ga-custom4D  
ga-custom4E  
ga-custom4F  
ga-custom4G  
ga-custom4H  
pageViewCount  
sessionCount  |  These cookies allows users to interact with Volkswagen Vans website.   
s_cc  
s_fid  
s_sq  
s_vi  
s_ppv  
sc_c68  
sc_cmdep  
sc_fv  
sc_prop32  
sc_tsev  
sc_tsp  
sc_tsv  
sc_v41  
sc_prevpage  
s_dl  
s_depth  
s_vnum  
s_invisit  
sc_appvn  
_sp_id.a60a  
_sp_ses.a60a  
_s3_id.60.0a15  
_s3_ses.60.0a15  
_s3_id.60.c5c7  
_s3id.60.8fa5  
smartSignalsTest  
smartSignalsUid  
SmartUID  
selectedInfotainmentSystem  
selectedPhone  |  These cookies allows users to interact with the global Volkswagen website.   
_hjClosedSurveyInvites  
_hjDonePolls  
_hjMinimizedPolls  
_hjDoneTestersWidgets  
_hjMinimizedTestersWidgets  
_hjDoneSurveys  
_hjIncludedInSample  
_hjShownFeedbackMessage  |  These cookies allow us to analyse what users do on our website and to obtain feedback from users.   
  
Our social media channels are the best place to find out about all the latest Volkswagen news and products and to share your thoughts, pictures and videos.

We strive to create an open and transparent space for our community to engage; we will, however, remove posts that aren’t related to Volkswagen and/or violate the Terms and Conditions of Facebook. We have provided more detail on these guidelines and our moderation policy, below.

**KEY COMMUNITY GUIDELINES**

  * Make sure you don't post any personal information, including specific information on your car, telephone numbers or address information
  * Please don't post anything that's offensive, abusive, deceptive, defamatory, obscene, menacing, illegal, fraudulent, misleading, threatening, racist, sexist, or in any way discriminatory
  * Please don't post any adverts, spam or links to irrelevant websites
  * Please don’t post any commercial solicitations
  * Keep it relevant - if you post something that is off-topic, then it may be removed

**MODERATION POLICY**

**If contributors persistently ignore our community guidelines, we will seriously consider having posting privileges on our social media channels withdrawn.**

We want to maintain an open and transparent conversation across our channels, but if the nature of your content infringes on the over-arching experience for our fans and followers we reserve the right to take action to mitigate against this happening. One of our customer service team may be in touch if an issue comes up in relation to our community guidelines.

**We will, when necessary, remove comments from our social media content.**

If a response to a Volkswagen UK social media post or a comment published on the community section of our Facebook page is perceived as breaching the community guidelines set out above, then it will be removed by the community moderation team, which will be carried out in the interests of maintaining the community standards appropriate for the vast majority of the people who visit.
